Contact

karenjdarden@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/karendarden-17a33826 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Hospitals
Healthcare
Clinical Research

Karen Darden

Walden University - MSN Nurse Education; Grand Canyon University - Ed.D currently in progress.

Lynchburg, Virginia

Summary

Experienced Travel Nurse with a demonstrated history of working in the staffing and recruiting industry. Skilled in Microsoft Word, Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS), Cerner, Critical Care Nursing, and Healthcare Management. Strong healthcare services professional with a Master of Science in Nursing (MSN) focused in Nursing Education from Walden University.

Experience

Medical Solutions Registered Nurse, Travel Nurse April 2011 - Present (9 years 4 months)

Centra Health

Travel RN

RN

November 2005 - April 2011 (5 years 6 months)

Registered Nurse. Worked at Centra's two Lynchburg hospitals. Worked in MICU upon arrival to Lynchburg, the Oncology unit, and the Long Term Acute Care Hospital (LTACH). Job description: Patient careplanning and implementation of plans through tasks including comprehensive health assessments, computerized documentation; administration of medications, blood transfusions, intravenous therapies including total parenteral nutrition, enteral feedings; patient monitoring (telemetry, vital signs, lab values); wound care, tracheostomy care, and responding to alarms/emergencies. Assumed responsibility of primary charge role on nights for two years with additional job description as follows: organization of staff and workload, teaching nursing skills and serving as resource for nursing staff.

Maxim Healthcare Services
Clinical Nursing Supervisor
January 2005 - October 2005 (10 months)

Responsible for supervision of ongoing skilled (visit every 30 days) and unskilled (visit every 60 days) cases. Supervision of nursing staff and nursing care provided for all assigned cases. Assist Director of Nursing (DON) as required with duties such as skills training for staff and tuberculosis testing. Assure JCAHO and CACH standards are maintained at all times. Open new skilled and unskilled cases. One time visits for assessment, patient teaching, etc., as referred. Patient teaching visits in cooperation with pharmaceutical companies to teach patients how to properly handle, store, prepare, and inject medications such as Betaseron, Embrel, Raptiva, and Fuzeon.

Raritan Bay Medical Center

RN

June 2004 - October 2005 (1 year 5 months)

ER Hold / Float RN position. Full time, night shift. Intravenous and central venous catheter certification; local critical care certification, BLS and ACLS. Changed to part time and to 3 -11 shift January 2005 when taking on full time Clinical Supervisor position with Maxim.

Loving Care Agency, Inc

RN / LPN

July 2001 - October 2005 (4 years 4 months)

Provide skilled nursing pediatric homecare to various children and babies, most of whom were ventilator-dependent. Major duties similar to those listed in next job description.

Maxim Healthcare Services

RN / LPN

January 2003 - September 2004 (1 year 9 months)

Provide skilled nursing care in home setting to ventilator- dependent toddler with diagnosis of Spinal Muscular Atrophy. Major duties included: Care planning and implementation of care plan through tasks including CPT every four hours with coughalator use and suction, tracheostomy and gastrostomy tube (Mickey button) changes, tracheostomy and gastrostomy tube care, continuous g-tube feedings, monitoring and maintaining ventilator with humidification, airway management, administration of medications via g-tube or nebulizer, bathing, dressing, transferring, and nursing documentation.

Interim HealthCare

LPN

March 2002 - March 2003 (1 year 1 month)

Per diem staffing work at local hospitals and nursing homes.

Raritan Bay Medical Center

Licensed Practical Nurse

February 2001 - March 2003 (2 years 2 months)

on a medical surgical unit. I obtained IV certification during this employment.

Education

Grand Canyon University

Doctor of Education - EdD, Doctor of Education in Teaching and Learning with an Emphasis in Adult Learning · (2017 - 2020)

Walden University

Master of Science in Nursing (MSN), Nursing Education · (2009 - 2012)

Excelsior College

Associates Degree, Nursing · (2001 - 2003)

Monmouth County Vocational School

Diploma, Licensed Practical/Vocational Nurse Training · (1999 - 2000)

Union County College

Associates Degree, Nursing/Biology; Biology · (1975 - 1977)